<tools>
  <tool name="browser_action">
    <description>Perform browser actions using a Playwright-controlled browser with multiple tabs.
  The browser is PERSISTENT and remains active until explicitly closed, allowing for
  multi-step workflows and long-running processes across multiple tabs.</description>
    <parameters>
      <parameter name="action" type="string" required="true">
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="url" type="string" required="false">
        <description>Required for 'launch', 'goto', and optionally for 'new_tab' actions. The URL to launch the browser at, navigate to, or load in new tab. Must include appropriate protocol (e.g., http://, https://, file://).</description>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="coordinate" type="string" required="false">
        <description>Required for 'click', 'double_click', and 'hover' actions. Format: "x,y" (e.g., "432,321"). Coordinates should target the center of elements (buttons, links, etc.). Must be within the browser viewport resolution. Be very careful to calculate the coordinates correctly based on the previous screenshot.</description>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="text" type="string" required="false">
        <description>Required for 'type' action. The text to type in the field.</description>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="tab_id" type="string" required="false">
        <description>Required for 'switch_tab' and 'close_tab' actions. Optional for other actions to specify which tab to operate on. The ID of the tab to operate on. The first tab created during 'launch' has ID "tab_1". If not provided, actions will operate on the currently active tab.</description>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="js_code" type="string" required="false">
        <description>Required for 'execute_js' action. JavaScript code to execute in the page context. The code runs in the context of the current page and has access to the DOM and all page-defined variables and functions. The last evaluated expression's value is returned in the response.</description>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="duration" type="string" required="false">
        <description>Required for 'wait' action. Number of seconds to pause execution. Can be fractional (e.g., 0.5 for half a second).</description>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="key" type="string" required="false">
        <description>Required for 'press_key' action. The key to press. Valid values include: - Single characters: 'a'-'z', 'A'-'Z', '0'-'9' - Special keys: 'Enter', 'Escape', 'ArrowLeft', 'ArrowRight', etc. - Modifier keys: 'Shift', 'Control', 'Alt', 'Meta' - Function keys: 'F1'-'F12'</description>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="file_path" type="string" required="false">
        <description>Required for 'save_pdf' action. The file path where to save the PDF.</description>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="clear" type="boolean" required="false">
        <description>For 'get_console_logs' action: whether to clear console logs after retrieving them. Default is False (keep logs).</description>
      </parameter>
    </parameters>
    <returns type="Dict[str, Any]">
      <description>Response containing: - screenshot: Base64 encoded PNG of the current page state - url: Current page URL - title: Current page title - viewport: Current browser viewport dimensions - tab_id: ID of the current active tab - all_tabs: Dict of all open tab IDs and their URLs - message: Status message about the action performed - js_result: Result of JavaScript execution (for execute_js action) - pdf_saved: File path of saved PDF (for save_pdf action) - console_logs: Array of console messages (for get_console_logs action)   Limited to 50KB total and 200 most recent logs. Individual messages truncated at 1KB. - page_source: HTML source code (for view_source action)   Large pages are truncated to 100KB (keeping beginning and end sections).</description>
    </returns>
    <notes>
  Key rules:
  1. Browser is PERSISTENT — maintains state until 'close' action
  2. Start with 'launch', end with 'close'. One action per call.
  3. Click coordinates must come from most recent screenshot (center of element)
  4. Tab management: launch creates tab_1, new tabs are tab_2, tab_3, etc.
  5. JS execution: last expression is returned (no return statement needed)
  6. For form filling: click field first, then 'type' to enter text
  7. ALWAYS close browser when done
    </notes>
    <examples>
  <function=browser_action>
  <parameter=action>launch</parameter>
  <parameter=url>https://example.com</parameter>
  </function>

  <function=browser_action>
  <parameter=action>click</parameter>
  <parameter=coordinate>450,300</parameter>
  </function>

  <function=browser_action>
  <parameter=action>type</parameter>
  <parameter=text>user@example.com</parameter>
  </function>

  <function=browser_action>
  <parameter=action>execute_js</parameter>
  <parameter=js_code>({images: document.images.length, links: document.links.length})</parameter>
  </function>
    </examples>
  </tool>
</tools>
